Jonathan Clark

Software Developer

Highly experienced professional with 12+ years background in Management and customer satisfaction. Proficient in using a wide variety of tools to provide efficient, cost effective solutions to boost productivity and overall organizational efficiency.

Development Projects

Contacts Management CLI

Command Line Interface written solely in Java for the purpose of managing a list of contacts and phone numbers. This project explores concepts of *Menu Driven List Manipulation* as well as using *File I/O* to manage data from sources existing outside of the program. What makes this project especially unique is its ability to validate user input to ensure a smooth, concise user experience.

Weather Map Project

Single page web application that utilizes HTML,CSS,JQuery, and AJAX. This project accesses multiple open-source APIs to provide an in-depth weather forecast. Users can search and update a 5 Day Weather Forecast, in real time, based on either a searched location or a location set via pin-drop on an embedded map.

Mobile Design Project

Single page application that focuses entirely on building a page that is fully responsive across multiple viewports. This web application hones in on complex styling and positioning concepts using Bootstrap, HTML, and CSS.

Professional Experience

Tycoon Flats - San Antonio, TX

FOH Manager, Bar Manager / Feb 2017 - Present

- Training and developing Crew Members, Assistant Managers, and Management trainees
- Plan, supervise, and coordinate overall daily operations
- Interact with the management from other departments and develop solid working relationships with them
- Monitor weekly inventories and verify accuracy through point-of-sale system
- Exercise supervisory authority over restaurant and bar, implement training manuals, and conduct staff meetings

Double Dave's Pizzaworks - San Antonio, TX

General Manager / October 2007 - Nov 2016

- Interviewed, hired, trained, and managed approximately 20+ employees
- Developed training materials
- Appraising employee work performance to ensure they perform at optimal levels
- Maintained accurate inventory by conducting weekly counts of over 200 items
- Implemented inventory procedure changes resulting in decreased inventory times and decreased inaccurate data
- Responsible for employee conflict resolution

(210) 518 8220

jonathan.b.clark1127@gmail.com

in LinkedIn/JaneSmith

github.com/jclark127

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,

JavaScript, ¡Query,

Java SE, Java EE (Servlets, JSP), Spring, Thymeleaf, MySQL,

Object-Oriented Programming, Test-Driven Development, Version Control with Git, Paired Programming

Education

Codeup

Certificate of Completion Nov 2021 - May 2022

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 22-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development.

San Antonio College

Occupational Skills Award - Java Aug 2019 - March 2021

A Certificate program focused on fundamentals in programming and web development, as well as Advanced OOP concepts in Java.